pehub.com 2015-09-05

# Privacy statement | Thomson Reuters Financial & Risk

Scope

Your privacy is important to Thomson Reuters, and we go to great lengths to protect it. This Privacy Statement applies to the collection of personal information via products, websites, competitions, events, webinars and some mobile applications operated by **Thomson Reuters Financial and Risk Businesses**.

**For the purposes of this Privacy Statement, Thomson Reuters Corporation (Ontario) is considered a joint controller with Reuters Limited (England) AND Thomson Reuters Finance S.A. (Luxembourg), which form part of the Thomson Reuters Group of Companies. Contact information can be found below.**

Our products and/or websites may contain links to sites maintained by others, or by other parts of Thomson Reuters. This Privacy Statement does not reflect the privacy practices of those products and sites. It also does not cover the information practices at [Reuters.com](http://www.reuters.com/privacy-policy "Reuters.com Privacy Statement"), [ThomsonReuters.com](http://thomsonreuters.com/privacy-statement/ "Thomson Reuters Privacy 

Policy") or [World-check.com](http://www.world-check.com/privacy-statement "World-Check.com Privacy Statement"). Please see the links above or via these sites for their specific Privacy Statements.

Highlights

**What personal information is collected and how is that information used?**

  * We collect information about individuals, users and professional's in variety of ways including but not limited to: direct from the individuals (for example, when ordering a product, registering an account, using the products, or signing up for a newsletter), from your employer, publicly available information, and through cookies, and/or similar technology.
  * We use the information primarily to provide you with a personalized experience that delivers the information, resources, and services that are most relevant and helpful to you.
  * We do not share with others any of the information you provide, unless we say so in this Privacy Statement, or when we believe in good faith that the law requires it.

More Details

**How is my personal information protected?**

  * We maintain administrative, technical and physical safeguards to protect against loss, misuse or unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration or destruction of the personal information you or your employer provides to us.
  * Thomson Reuters complies with Data Protection/Privacy regulations, laws and industry best practices in respects to security around personal information.
  * If you are located in the European Economic Area ("EEA"), or a country with data protection/privacy law, we may transfer your personal information to countries that may not guarantee the same level of protection for personal information as the one in which you reside. By giving your information you consent to these transfers.

More Details

**Who has access to the personal information?**

  * We will not sell, rent, or lease mailing lists or other customer data to others, and we will not make your personal information available to any unaffiliated parties, except our approved agents, suppliers and contractors, or as otherwise described in this Privacy Statement.
  * We rely on some of our affiliates for support of the products and services we offer, and we share some of our back- office functions with other Thomson Reuters companies; in accordance with this Privacy Statement
  * We will not disclose any personal information or information about your usage of our products, websites or mobile applications to unaffiliated third parties, except as necessary to enhance the product experience, service the legal agreement between us and your employer, to enforce the terms of use, to meet our obligations to content and technology providers, or as required by law.

More Details

**How may you correct, amend, or delete your personal information, or update your preferences?**

  * You may amend update or delete your information at any time via the products or services, via our Customer Center, or via the Marketing Preference Center link at the bottom of any email communication.
  * If you have problems with the preference center please contact us.
  * If you have any additional questions or concerns related to this statement and/or our practices, [email us](mailto:privacy.enquiries@thomsonreuters.com "Privacy Officer") or write to the data controller stated above to the attention of the Global Privacy Officer.
  * Should you require a copy of the Privacy Statement in a language other than English please [contact us](mailto:privacy.enquiries@thomsonreuters.com "Privacy Officer").

More Details

Back to Top

Full Privacy Statement

**What personal information does Thomson Reuters collect and how do we use it?**

We collect information about individuals, users and professional's in a variety of ways: including but not limited to: direct from the individuals (for example, when ordering a product, registering an account, using a product, or signing up for a newsletter), from your employer, publicly available information, and through cookies, and/or similar technology. We use the information primarily to provide you with a personalized experience that delivers the information, resources, and services that are most relevant and helpful to you. We don't share any of the information you provide with others, unless we say so in this Privacy Statement, or when we believe in good faith that the law requires it.

**User-supplied information**

When you register for our services - directly or via your Employer, or order products via our sites or directly with us, we ask you to provide some personal information, for example, your name, address, phone number, email address, if required payment card information, and/or certain additional categories of information resulting from use of our products, websites and services, such as research requests. We keep this information in a contact database for future reference, as needed. 

**Marketing**

We may use certain information you provide to offer you products and services that we believe may be of interest to you or for market research purposes. If you don't wish to receive such offers or to be contacted directly, you may opt out (unsubscribe) as described below.

**To update your preferences for email communications for our products, services, news updates, bulletins, and reports please go to the preference center link found on each specific email communication.**

**Otherwise see the paragraph below on 'HOW MAY I CORRECT, AMEND, OR DELETE MY PERSONAL INFORMATION AND/OR UPDATE MY PREFERENCES?'**

In certain countries if you use our products and/or services in the course of your employment, Thomson Reuters will only send you unsolicited marketing via email if your employer has given its consent for you to receive email communications from Thomson Reuters, or if your employer has allowed Thomson Reuters to contact you directly and gain your consent to receive marketing.

If you contact us for customer support, we may ask you to provide information about your computer or about the issues you are trying to resolve. This information is necessary to help us answer your questions. We may record your requests and our responses for quality control and training purposes.

Some Thomson Reuters products and/or websites make messenger, chat rooms, forums, message boards, or news groups available to you. Please remember that any information disclosed in these areas is public. You should exercise caution when disclosing personal information in these areas. Don't disclose information in these public forums that might be considered confidential.

**Usage and Web server logs**

When you visit our products or web sites, we may track information about your usage and/or visit, and store that information on in usage or web server logs, which are records of the activities on our products or sites. Our servers automatically capture and save the information electronically. Some examples of the information we may collect include:

  * Your unique Internet protocol address
  * The name of your unique Internet service provider
  * The city, state, and country from which you access our website
  * The kind of browser or computer you use
  * The number of links you click within the site
  * The date and time of your visit
  * The web page from which you arrived to our site
  * The pages you viewed on the site
  * Certain searches/queries that you conducted via our product(s) and/or website(s)

The information we collect in usage or web server logs helps us administer the product and site, analyze its usage, protect the product and/or website and its content from inappropriate use, and improve the user's experience.  

**Thomson Reuters Messenger**

If you are a user of this product, any personal information you post can be visible to other users. This privacy policy will not apply in these instances. Please refer to the Terms of Use.

In addition, Thomson Reuters may be required by your Employer and/or by laws or regulations to store messages, and conversations to meet regulatory and compliance obligations for a certain period of time. This includes public and private interaction between users. Moderators, Compliance and/or Legal professionals in your business may have access to historical or live conversations.  

To develop the product and/or communities, Thomson Reuters may analyze certain data.  

**Cookies**

In order to offer and provide a customize and personal service through our products and websites, we may use cookies to store and help track information about you.

A cookie is a small text file sent to your device that we use to store limited information about your use of the product or website. We use cookies to provide you with certain functionality (such as to enable access to secure log-in areas and to save you having to re-enter information into product or website forms) and to personalize our product or website content. Without cookies, this functionality would be unavailable.  

**By using our products and websites you agree that we can place these types of cookies on your device.**  

**Third Party Services**

We may also use analytics tools provided by Google, Inc. ("Google") or other similar providers. Analytics tools serve cookies through our products or website and collects aggregated data on an anonymized basis about users and visitors' use of the product or website. The data collected enables us to understand aggregated user or visitor activity and how we may improve our product or website offering. This data is collected and used on an anonymized, aggregated basis only and does not enable any user or visitor to be personally identified.  

In addition, we may also use marketing automation tools (specific Company information can be given upon request). These companies serve cookies to profile users or visitors' interests and activity. We use data collected through these cookies to serve users or visitors with information, new articles and advertising tailored to their specific needs and requirements.  This data is collected on an anonymized basis, except where users or visitors have previously registered to receive marketing communications from us or subsequently choose to do so.  Where this is the case, cookies set may enable us to identify the user or visitor. Where visitors have registered to receive marketing communications from us, we use the tools provided by these companies to send targeted e-mail marketing and track the effectiveness of our e-mail campaigns, including through the use of clear gif images in e-mails.

You have the right to refuse or disable cookies served through our products or website although, if you choose to do so, certain functionality may become unavailable to you. As the means by which you may do this vary from browser to browser, we recommend that you visit your browser's help menu for further information.

Our email and promotional communications may also include "Clear Image" gifs to track results of an email campaign. To turn off gifs you can do so in the email itself, or visit your email client's help menu. 

We respect your right to choose whether or not to accept cookies and clear gifs.

**Please note that if you do not set your browser and e-mail settings to disable cookies and clear gifs, you will be indicating your consent to receive them.**  

If you wish to find out more about cookies and clear gifs, you may like to visit [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/ "www.allaboutcookies.org"), an independent third party resource that explains what cookies and clear gifs are and how you may manage them. Please note that we are not responsible for, and have no control over, the content of this third party website.

Back to Top

**How does Thomson Reuters Financial & Risk protect the personal information that it collects?**

We have implemented certain appropriate security measures to help protect your personal information from accidental loss and from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure. For example, some of our products and/or websites are protected with Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) technology. Also, we store the information about you in a data center with restricted access and appropriate monitoring, and we use a variety of technical security measures to secure your data. In addition, we use intrusion detection and virus protection software.

Also, please note that we may store and process your personal information in systems located outside of your home country. However, regardless of where storage and processing may occur, we take appropriate steps to ensure that your information is protected, consistent with the principles set forth under this Statement, and as required under Data Protection/Privacy laws.

**Transfer of personal information to other countries**

If you are located in the European Economic Area ("EEA"), or a country with data protection/privacy law, we may transfer your personal information to countries that may not guarantee the same level of protection for personal information as the one in which you reside. **By giving your information you consent to these transfers.** Thomson Reuters will only transfer personal information to the extent it is necessary to fulfill the purpose outlined above.

Recipients of data are other companies in the Thomson Reuters group of companies and third party service providers.

We will take appropriate steps to provide an adequate level of protection to all personal information against the standards set within the EEA, as a minimum. No matter where you reside your data shall be processed in accordance with the provisions set out in this Privacy Statement.

Back to Top

**Who has access to the personal information?**

We will not sell, rent, or lease mailing lists or other customer data to others, and we will not make your personal information available to any unaffiliated parties, except as follows:

  * When the data is collected from publicly available domains including but not limited to  websites, company directories, company registrars, publicly available government lists, search engines and similar technology.
  * To agents and/or contractors who may use it on our behalf or in connection with their relationship with us (for example, we may use third parties to help us with promotional campaigns).
  * As required by law, in a matter of public safety or policy, as needed in connection with the transfer of our business assets (for example, if we are acquired by another company or if we are liquidated during bankruptcy proceedings), or if we believe in good faith that sharing the data is necessary to protect our rights or property.

We also rely on some of our affiliates for support of the products and services we offer, and we share some of our back-office functions with other Thomson Reuters companies. Our affiliates are all required to preserve the confidentiality of any personal information they may access in accordance with this Statement.

We will not disclose any information about your usage to unaffiliated third parties, except as necessary to enhance the product experience, service the legal agreement between us and your employer, service the account, collaboration between Thomson Reuters products, to enforce the terms of use, to meet our obligations to content and technology providers, or as required by law.

We may also use statistics regarding usage for product development and enhancement purposes.

Your access to some of our products, services and content may be password protected. We recommend that you refrain from disclosing your username(s) and password(s) to anyone. We also recommend that you sign out of your product, account or service at the end of each session. You may also wish to close your product terminal or browser window when you have finished your work, especially if you share a computer with someone else or if you are using a computer in a public place.

Back to Top

**How may I correct, amend, or delete my personal information and/or update my preferences?**

You can amend, update or delete your personal information whenever you like. Please go to your profile settings in your product or services being used. Or contact your Customer Center for assistance.

**To update your preferences for email communications for our products, services, news updates, bulletins, and reports please go to the preference center link found on each specific email communication.**

In certain countries if you use our products and/or services in the course of your employment, Thomson Reuters will only send you unsolicited marketing via email if your employer has given its consent for you to receive email communications from Thomson Reuters, or if your employer has allowed Thomson Reuters to contact you directly and gain your consent to receive marketing.

**If you are having problems with the preference center link – please email the following with a copy of the email communication you received:**

**Safe Harbor Certification**

Thomson Reuters US Financial and Risk Businesses are Thomson Reuters Markets LLC, Thomson Reuters Global Markets Inc, and Thomson Reuters G R C Inc.

Thomson Reuters US Financial and Risk Businesses and their wholly owned and controlled subsidiaries comply with the U.S-EU Safe Harbor Framework and the U.S-Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries and Switzerland.Thomson Reuters Financial and Risk Businesses have certified that they adhere to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view certification, please visit <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/>.

**QUESTIONS?**

If you would like to see the data Thomson Reuters holds on you (there can be a charge for this service) or if you have any questions or concerns related to this statement and/or our practices, or a complaint or dispute, please [email us](mailto:privacy.enquiries@thomsonreuters.com "Privacy Officer") or write to the data controller stated above to the attention of the Global Privacy Officer.

**TRANSLATIONS**

Should you require a copy of the Privacy Statement in a language other than English please [email us](mailto:privacy.enquiries@thomsonreuters.com "Privacy Officer").

**PRIVACY STATEMENT CHANGES**

If Thomson Reuters information practices change in a significant way, we will post the policy changes here. Thomson Reuters reserves the right to change this Privacy Statement at any time by posting an updated version here. All previous versions will not be valid.  

This Privacy Statement was last updated on 29th May 2015.

Back to Top
